

# Olivier Penhoat

CTO / Director of Developer Experience

## About me

I am passionate about **web development** and **IT architectures**, **experienced** in **agile** team **management** and **coaching**, able to create a **digital platform** from Think stage, to Build, Devops and Run.

**CTO** resolutely craftsman, capable of developing and carrying a real **product vision** in contexts with **high strategic stakes**.

In my favorite playground we often find:

JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Jest, REST, GraphQL, Docker, Redis, MongoDb, ReactJS, Zsh, Portainer, Traefik, Google Cloud

# Bio

**⊞** Age

52

**☑** Email

openhoat@gmail.com

**Q** City

Bordeaux, France

**Status** 

Married with 3 kids

## Skills

Deno **NodeJS** JavaScript / TypeScript Docker / K8s **ReactJS AngularJS VueJS** Redis COMFORTABLE MongoDB **Neural networks / Machine Learning** AWS, Google Cloud, Azure DevOps, Digital Ocean Shell **REST** MASTER GraphQL

	MASTER	
Svelte		
	MAÎTRISE	
HTML 5		
TITIVIL 3		
	MASTER	
CSS 3		
FAMILIAR		
2 " 1		
Scrum, Kanban		
СОМГО	RTABLE	
Markdown		
	MASTER	
Jest		
Jest		
	EXPERT	
Python, Go		
FAMILIAR		
GitLab CI, GitHub Actions, A	Azure Pipelines	
	MAÎTRISE	

# Soft skills

Rigor & method
Active listening
Logical & analytical sense
Pedagogy
Open mind
Autonomy
Adaptability
Decision making
Honesty
Team spirit & transparency
Communication
Empathy

## Experiences

## O CTO / Director of Developer Experience at Niji Bordeaux

Since 2021

- Extreme Architecture & Head of Tech of a connected mirror app / makeup experience
- Federation of internal communities of developers and architects at the national level (tech days, tech animation)
- Management of developers, support for skills development & curricula
- Building of a multi API federation platform / Unity Ads, Ironsource, Vungle, Google,
  TikTok, ... / NodeJS / PostgreSQL / Google Cloud
- Launch of Niji Tech program and associated blog: Niji.tech
- Implementation of a Custom Activity SalesForce Marketing Cloud NodeJS / React / Redis / AWS
- Mentoring and coaching of ReactJS / NodeJS fullstack dev teams
- Implementation of a NodeJS / MongoDb / NestJS REST API backend to collect Covid tests
- Support for technical interviews of candidates in hiring process
- · Code audits, flash audits, due diligences

### CTO / Product Owner / Full stack engineer at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2015 - 2021

- Migration of the API gateway to TypeScript
- Design and implementation of the Digiposte authentication gateway
- Creation of the CN23 mobile web application for customs declaration on tablet
- Creation of the Okapi platform, Open API of the Digital Branch of La Poste Group (developer.laposte.fr)
- · Definition of the roadmap and business models
- Integration of billing solution, limiters, plugins
- BU Management: agile team, vision box
- Open innovation advocate
- Al training / fundamental neural networks
- Conferences / practice / katas
- API expertise: publication of white paper API design and training

 Stack: EcmaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, Reactjs, Webpack, Expressjs, Gitlab pipeline, Docker, ELK, Redis

#### IT Architect at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2014 - 2015

- IT Architecture for Digital Confidence (Digiposte, Digiposte Pass)
- Implementations of some POCs, intra consulting
- Management of the Open API POC project for the Group
- Implementation of the laposte.io
- Full stack expertise

#### Consultant at Octo Technology

2013

- · Technical architecture at Digiposte
- · Validation of technical choices
- · Coordination of performance tests
- Implementation of prototypes
- Coding of an URL shortener service for Octo
- Coding of a Dropbox / Digiposte synch webapp

#### Consultant Trainer at Valtech Training

2009 - 2013

- Training on over twenty courses J2EE, JS, Web, Factory Software, Quality, Security
- Areas of industry, insurance banking, service: Thalès, Dassault, NDS, Generali, CDC, Orange, ...
- R&D: Java Quality, Android, Mobile Web, Web Hacking, NodeJS, Extreme Java
- Technical coaching
- Seminars: Android, Cross-platform development, NodeJS
- · Design and production of the desktop and mobile website valtech-training.fr
- · Implementation of the software factory

#### Software factory chief at Le Crédit Lyonnais

2008 - 2009

- Management of a support and assistance team for tech people
- Implementation of changes in the LCL software factory
- Study on the exportability of the software factory in offshore projects
- Animation of working groups around SOA, WOA, REST

## New services and bank products chief at Crédit Agricole S.A.

2005 - 2008

- Project management Coordination of Multiple Access Banking and Mobile Internet projects
- Definition of product plans, animation of technical committees, realization of POCs, participation in Architecture Working Groups
- BAM projects, electronic statement, electronic signature, iPhone site
- · RESTful SSO solution reengineering

## Technology solutions projects chief at Entenial

2001 - 2005

- Operational supervision of Web developers within the "multi-channel" pole
- Developer training in Java / Beanshell / Taglib / JSTL / MVC2
- Participation in construction work, and assistance to MOA

#### Technical project chief at MDEO-Zentropy

2000 - 2001

- Operational supervision of web projects
- · Creation of the nabab.fr website
- Design and realization of an ORM

#### iNet technologies consultant at Cetal Conseil

1999 - 2000

- Advising banks (Crédit Agricole, CCF, Société Générale) in the field of iNet technologies
- Training of internal teams in web development
- Redesign of the BancoPC site (www.ccf.fr) at a fixed price

## Online banking project chief at Crédit Commercial de France

1999 - 2000

- Project management of Distance Banking projects within IT Studies
- Projects: BancoPC, WAP, Webroker
- Changeover to the Euro, a 2000

#### Engineer at Isthme / Steria

1994 - 1996

Development of telematics and client / server applications in the banking and tertiary sector

# Education

Engineer Epita Paris

1993

Industrial computer science and artificial intelligence

BTS Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1991

Industrial computer science

Bac Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1989

F2 Électronique (mention bien)

## Contact

□ openhoat@gmail.com